DAVID CORNISH FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT



dcornish84@gmail.com

Inkedin.com/in/david-L-cornish

github.com/dcornish84

ABOUT ME

The path to software development has been long and winding, but a few things have crystalized along the way. I need an outlet for my creativity, I love new technology, and I thrive in a team based environment. Development is a team sport and my experience in a fast paced customer service environment as well as my experience de-escalating patients really informs my approach to team dynamics and how to handle stress within a group. My time on Music Row really stoked my love of learning about new technology and tweaking things until they're just right.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

RecordCollector. A web application built in React used to compile album information in a catalogue and wishlist format. I built this application to help manage my vinyl collection and to avoid those moments when I enter a store and forget what I have and what I want. Utilizing the Discogs API I was able to acquire album information and then save it to a catalogue or wishlist JSON database with full CRUD functionality. Addtional technology used includes JSX, CSS, and Reactstrap.

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

6 MONTH FULL STACK BOOTCAMP | AUG 2019 - FEB 2020

Group Projects

- Welcome to Nashville. Worked with a team to create a tourism application for a client interested in the sports scene in Nashville. My role was to utilize the Ticketmaster API to create a music itinerary relevant to the client's interests. Built with Javascript, HTML, and CSS.
- Nutshell/Nutshell React. Worked with a team to create an application for a goth sweet 16 party. The application displays user specific news, task list, event list, chat, and friends list. My role was to flesh out the event list. Each module utilized CRUD functionality. Built with Javascript, HTML, and CSS. We then built another application using React with the same CRUD functionality and modules. I provided a working module for the group to then use as a template for the rest of the project. Built with HTML, React.js, and Reactstrap.

OMNI HOTELS AND RESORTS F&B MANAGER | JUL 2016 - JUL 2019

- Uncovered employee strengths and put them in positions to succeed. Handled onboard training and continued development. Managed a team of 20-25 employees.
- Provided expedient service in a high volume, fast paced convention hotel
- Projected sales and ordered products and supplies within budget

CUMBERLAND HEIGHTS TREATMENT CENTER QUALITY MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST | JUN 2015 - JUL 2016

- Completed data analysis using Excel to compile monthly breakdowns of Patient Satisfaction Surveys, Incident Reports, Metrics, and Chart Audits
- Maintained and updated Policies and Procedures for the entire company
- Inspected treatment facilities to ensure they were compliant with state

CLINICAL ASSOCIATE

JAN 2014 - JUN 2015

- Conducted 16 educational and experiential therapy groups a month
- State certified Ropes Course Instructor, utilizing certification in several experiential groups
- Utilized de-escalation techniques to ensure the well being of patients and staff

16TH EDGE STUDIOS AUDIO ENGINEER | MAY 2011 - MAR 2014

 Utilized ProTools, UAD plugins, Logic, outboard gear such as LA2A and 1176 compressors to record, edit, and mix tracks. Booked clients, maintained gear.

EDUCATION